I love all my friends.
And welcome to exercise number 21 in this exercise, we are asked to find the time complexity of the
function some digits.
So this function it and imperative a perimeter and and and return the sum.
So what is the sum?
It is the sum of the digits.
How many digits and in the number that you entered.
And so it will come.
I will calculate that log.
So log 100 is two because we have two digits after the the one, because 100 divided by 10 is divided
by 10 is 10.
So it is two digits after the division.
OK, so let's start solving.
So post the video and please try to solve this by your own and command the your solution.
I hope you like solve this question and you know it.
OK.
Awaiting your comments.
We start, in sum, equal to zero.
This is of one.
OK.
Return some of the.
The while loop here will determine the complexity of this question and order and greater than zero.
Well, while and greater than zero.
We have some equal to this than the old sum plus and modular 10.
So we are defining the entered and right then and now the new and with divided by 10.
So every time this loop, the sum will add the old sum, plus an modular 10 and an.
Is divided every time by 10.
So as I told you to solve all these questions, you need to take an example take an equal to 100.
OK, so.
I will make a table here and is 100 at the first iteration.
It is greater than zero.
Yes.
So as the sum?
Is equal to zero.
OK.
During that first iteration, the sum is.
This is the first iteration iteration I.
This is there is no iteration this initial and the first iteration.
And part of the sum becomes.
The old some some is equal to the old, some glass and modular 10.
So the old sum is zero because we have initialized this hazier plus.
And modulo 10 100 divided by 10 is 10.
And there is no remained so.
And modulo 10 is zero.
OK.
So zero plus zero sum is zero.
OK, now is divided by 10.
So this.
Is equal to and equal to the old and divided by 10.
100, divided by 10 is 10.
OK.
This is the first iteration, the second iteration going up and is greater than zero.
Yes.
So 10 greater than zero.
Go and make a game that code execute, this code sum is equal.
The old sum is equal to sort of than you sum is equal to the old sum plus and modulo 10 old some.
Term is zero.
OK.
Zero.
Plus and Modular 10.
And it's 10 then modular, 10 is equal to zero because 10 and divided by 10 is one.
There is no remain, so it is also easier.
OK.
If there's zero.
So the sum is and is divided that game by 10, so it is one.
Going up and there's one.
Yes.
So the third iteration and becomes one one greater than zero.
Yes, the sum is equal.
If something new is equal to this as old class and modular 10.
As old as you.
OK.
Because it's the plus and modulo 10 one, modulo 10 is one because one is not divided by 10.
OK, and the model, it becomes one.
So the sum is equal to one.
And.
Modular 10 has sort of divided by 10.
So one divided by 10 is equal to 0.1.
And since it is an end here and and so it took only the real part, the entire.
And becomes easier.
Going to the fourth iteration going up and greater than zero.
No, it is equal to zero.
So it stops that iteration.
OK.
And return some, so some will be returning like what?
And the value here is becoming like log 100 is equal to do, so we have two digits.
OK, we have two digits, so every number here could have up to its digits.
So an.
Equal or D is the digits equal to log?
And so that complexity of this program is.